one question: If they took the zeal from Ukraine, where did they take it? You had a famine in the
один вопрос Если у Украины забирали
Urals in the
увозили у вас был голодомор на урали в
thirties, I didn’t understand what people ate
тридцатые не не было понял А что ели
there, bread, potatoes, and where the bread
там хлеб картошку а откуда хлеб
was grown from. It’s interesting, it’s just that it
был выращивали Интересно просто у нас
turns out that today we have the Day of Remembrance for the
получается у нас сегодня вот День памяти
Victims of the Holodomor. Here too  they grew
жертв голодомора У нас тоже выращивали
bread, yes Yes, but for some reason
хлеб да Да но почему-то
Stalin took people’s bread at zero cost
Сталин забирал у людей хлеб под ноль Да
Yes, and he took it to Russia, it was he who took you away Well, he
и вывозил в Россию это он тебя забрал Ну
didn’t take it from us, so yes, that’s exactly what
а у нас не забирал так вот да вот именно
happens, he took it from us and took you away, fed you, and took it
то есть получается Он у нас забирал и
from you  But Well,
кормил у тебя именно забрал А вот Ну вот
look, if he took it from the Ukrainians,
да смотрите если он у украинцев забирал
then to whom did He give this bread? No, he didn’t
то кому Он отдавал этот хлеб Нет он не
take the Ukrainians from you, from me, but from
украинцев у тебя именно забрал у меня да
my ancestors, yes, but from
у моих предков забирал да да именно у
you,
теб
and you’re not dead, guess, guess, Yes, but
нело и ты вот не сдох прикинь прикиньте
what?  that's how you talk about it
Да а что А что вот вы так об этом
You didn't sting Well, it's good for you, but what's
Говорите вам не жал Ну вам хорошо а к
this for Oh you fir-trees Yes, there
что это Ах ты ёлки-палки Да так на Урале
was bread in the Urals Yes if That is, you had bread
был хлеб Да если То есть у тебя был хлеб
because they took bread from the Ukrainians at zero price
потому что у украинцев забирали под ноль
in order to feed you Moscow
хлеб для того чтобы накормить вас Москву
In  There was no Holodomor in Moscow today, Day of
В Москве не было голодомора сегодня День
Remembrance for Victims of the Holodomor for 90 years, you know
памяти жертв голодомора 90 лет знаете
the same events, yes I heard yes I heard I
эти же события да слышал да слышал
heard Yes, but an interesting question is
слышал Да а вот интересный вопрос вот
if in Ukraine they took away from the peasants at
если в Украине у крестьян забирали под
zero rate Yes, all the grain where it was taken out to
ноль Да всё зерно куда его вывозили
whom in Kazakhstan they say the same
кому в Казахстане говорят такие же
problems would be yes yes  in Kazakhstan these are the
проблемы бы да да в Казахстане вот такие
same in Ukraine in Kazakhstan where this
же в Украине в Казахстане то куда это
grain was exported in Kazakhstan in Kazakhstan
зерно вывозили в Казахстане в Казахстане
there were Russian peasants there this is where
там были русские крестьяне вот куда
they exported all this grain all A Remind me
вывозили эти это зерно всё А Напомни
what year this was, thirty-
какой это год был тридцать
third I
третий
don’t know
не знаю
listen they were doing it on the
слушай занимались на
ground where they were exporting
местах куда вывозили
this you are running away no I  I’m not running
это ты убегаешь нет Я не убегаю я
away, clarification from the
уточ изс
old
пожи
local
местна
Ukraine where
Украин ка
Ukraine Ukraine has been
мест Украина Украина сго года была
occupied by Russia for a year Yes, what kind of local
оккупирована Россией Да какое местное
leadership we had, only the occupation
руководство у нас только оккупационная
administration was understood by those
администрация была понимаешь те
who took Look where they
кто возили Смотри куда
took them, that’s where they fed this child
вывозили вот куда кого кормили
Yes, look at the places again,
этим дите Да на места ещё раз смотри
they took them to whom they sent  this grain was
забрали кому кому присылали это зерно
sent to whom the
кому присылали это знс руководители с
local leaders sent this grain. Look, yes, the Ukrainian
мест отправлять Вот смотри Да украинская
occupation administration collected
оккупационная администрация собирала
grain in Ukraine and where it sent
зерно в Украине и куда она отправляла
it. Well, what do they write there where they
его Ну и что пишут там куда они
sent it?
отправляли Ну куда ну вот и что куда
like now the DPR LPR set up by Russia
как сейчас ДНР лнр поставленная Россией
yes, like, sent to
да типа вот отправляла в
Moscow was not not Ukrainians on the ground No
Москву был не не украинцы на местах Нет
not Ukrainians on the ground no look again
не украинцы на местах нет смотри ещё раз
look at the
смотри
question for example Take for example
вопрос например Возьмите например
So I turn off the sound You don’t want to
Так я те отключаю звук Ты не хочешь меня
listen to me like yes So Where did you run away Yes
слушать типа да Значит Куда ты убежал Да
coons  like not the Ukrainians on the ground, but the
куны типа не украинцы на местах а
occupation administration, just like
оккупационная администрация также как
now in Drakh NRA and these like it in Crimea Yes, the
сейчас в Драх нра и этих как оно и Крыму
occupation administration and the DPR,
Да оккупационная администрация да ДНР
these beards and fluffs there, this is all the
вот эти там борода и пуши это всё
occupation administration Yes, which is
оккупационная администрация Да которая
now destroying the people of Donbass
сейчас да уничтожает людей Донбасса
Crimea and others also destroyed people
Крыма и других также уничтожали и людей
in  How are they afraid of Ukraine, but it’s very
в Украине как они типа боятся да очень
easy to say Well, where did they take it, even
же просто сказать Ну куда вывозили даже
if it was Ukraine who exported it there, where for whose
если это Украина там вывозила куда на на
gain, how is that in Russian, [ __ ] for
на чью корысть как это по-русски бляд в
Whose benefit they took the grain from the Ukrainian peasants at zero cost,
Чью пользу забирали зерно под ноль у
and today we have 90 years of memory Well
а куне у нас сегодня 90 лет памяти Ну
Day of Remembrance for the Victims of the Holodomor Yes, here I am with the
День памяти жертв голодомора Да вот я у
Russians, here you have where your relatives
Россиян вот у вас откуда родственники
come from, it’s already difficult, the truth is, the Holodomor is a very
родом уже тяжело правда голодомор очень
complex topic. I can’t understand no no no no no no
сложная тема Я не могу понять нет нет
my friend, not not not complicated,
нет нет нет друг мой не не не сложная
it’s just wasp Look, it’s setting my teeth on edge,
она просто ос Смотри вот оскомина да
look, I’m one question one question  If
смотри я один вопрос один вопрос Если у
grain was taken from Ukraine Ulya where it was
Украины забирали зерно Уля буде куда его
taken maybe Let's be
увозили может быть Давайте будем
hysterical they were taken away so don't be hysterical
истерить увозили так не истерить
I allow you not to be hysterical in the Volga region Where they
разрешаю вам не истерить в Поволжье Куда
were taken to the Volga region they took everything where they were
увозили в Поволжье увозили всё куда
taken to the Volga region I say on the
увозили в Поволжье же говорю на
Volga people were starving too Yeah I understand whether
Волгу люди голодали тоже Ага понял а в
they were taken to Moscow or
Москву увезли или
not  of course they took it everywhere So wait,
нет конечно везде увезли Так подождите
look at the question If in Moscow in the city of
смотри вопрос Если в Москве в городе
Moscow they didn’t grow grain in Ukraine
Москва не выращивали зерно на Украине
they grew wait stop in Ukraine
выращивали подожди стоп на Украине
they grew grain in Moscow they didn’t grow it
выращивали зерно в Москве не выращивали
in Ukraine they took away grain Yes in Ukraine those
в Украине забирали зерно Да в Украине
who died in Moscow as a result of the
погибших в Москве врезультате
Holodomor question or monologue question
голодомора вопрос или монолог вопрос
now I’m muting you  so that you
теперь я тебе отключал звук чтобы ты
listen to the
выслушал
question Lord, my God, what a thousand of
вопрос Господи Боже мой какой же тыш
trees and sticks there is nothing to answer Why there is nothing
ёлки-палки нечего ответить Почему нечего
How many died as a result of the
Сколько погибших в результате
Holodomor How many died in Moscow as a
голодомора Сколько в Москве погибших в
result of the Holodomor Yes, how
результате голодомора Да сколько какая
much does it matter, yes, that is, look it turns out
разница да то есть смотри получается
yes Why again Why Ukraine,
да Почему ещё раз Почему у Украины
Lord, and no one in Moscow  Why was Gomor in
Господи а в Москве никого Почему гомор в
what year was it thirty Trey we
каком году был ри вй тридцать Трей мы
just googled about this how much is the
сейчас про это так загугли сколько
population of Ukraine how much is the population of
население Украины сколько население
Ukraine I still turned off
Украины те ещ смо я те ещ раз отключил
the sound so you could listen properly
звук чтобы ты нормальненько послушал
look So you understand perfectly well Yes
смотри Значит ты прекрасно понимаешь Да
Why did you run away badge Yak them In short it’s
Что ку ты убежал бляха Як их Короче
being undermined  the topic is just crap Why
подрывается тема да просто капец А чего
so guys And what is he
так ребятки А что
saying from Ukraine they took bread from Ukraine and
такое говорит из Украины забирали хлеб и
transported it to the cart because there was
на повоз отвозили потому что там был
famine there but not you
голод да не вы
on Yes how much if there was famine in the country Yes
на Да сколько если был голод в стране Да
How many died from hunger in
Сколько погибших от голода в
Moscow after all somehow the famine brought on evenly
Москве ведь как-то наве голод равномерно
if only they could
бы
grow
расли
grain on ration cards Yes, for example, there are so many
по карточкам зерно Да например столько
portions of food Yes, they would give Why
там порцию еды Да давали бы Почему
they would take it away at zero rate Yes, they would take it out and
забирали под ноль Да вывозили и куда-то
send it somewhere like this, today in
отправляли вот так вот у нас сегодня в
Ukraine we celebrate the Day of Remembrance for Victims of the
Украине отмечают День памяти жертв
Holodomor for 90 years Yes, when
голодомора 90 лет Да когда вот у людей
they took away grain from people completely at zero level  and
забирали зерно полностью под ноли и
they exported you had something similar in the
вывозили у вас было что-то подобное во
Vladimir
Владимирской
region
обла
since 2002, I
с 2002 года насчёт Владимирской области
can’t say about the Vladimir region But I think in Russia
не могу сказать А так я думаю и в России
there was the Volga region and in Kazakhstan It was you
было Поволжье и в Казахстане Это было вы
yourself What city are your
сами Из какого города родом ваши
ancestors from Well, if you take my
предки Ну если взять моих
ancestors parents in  In Kazakhstan, a grandmother was born, let’s
предков родители в Казахстане родились
say, in Uzhgorod, a grandfather in about
бабушка допустим в Ужгороде дедушка в об
here, I can’t understand, there was hunger everywhere, as if in
вот негу понять был везде голод как бы в
Moscow, where they harvested wheat, there
Москве в которой пшеницу невали голода
was no hunger, but in Ukraine, where they grew
не было а в Украине в которой выращивали
wheat. Yes, there was famine because they took it away,
пшеницу Да голод был потому что забирали
how did it happen, you ask me that
как так получилось вы у меня это
yes yes Well  this is how we
спрашиваете да да Ну вот как как мы
think Well, how we think Listen, I
думаем Ну как мы думаем Слушайте я в то
didn’t live at that time, let’s say I can’t say
время не жил допустим я не могу сказать
how it is I’m telling you that my ancestors,
как там Я вам говорю что мои предки
let’s say, my grandmother and my grandfather’s grandmother
допустим бабушка бабушки дедушки мою
also experienced it,
пере тоже переживали это
sharpened
точили
IP I just want to understand, but I
ИП Я вот просто вот хочу понять вот не
can’t understand  if there was famine in the country Yes,
могу понять если был голод по стране Да
it somehow had to be everywhere Yes, and
он как-то должен был быть всюду Да и
most likely, and most likely, there
скорее всего да и скорее всего больше
should even be more in those places where
даже должен быть в тех местах где не
non-agricultural crops are not grown, that is, where
выращивают не аграрные да то есть где
wheat was grown, there should have been less famine
выращивали пшеницу голода меньше должно
because people had  what
было быть потому что у людей было что
is Listen, in the nineties Let's
есть Слушайте вот в девяностые годы
say all the big cities, let's say that
Допустим все большие города допустим то
Well, people were starving, let's say yes, but I found out
Ну люди голодали допустим да но я узнал
much later Yes, I suppose in
это гораздо позже Да я допустим в
the countryside I lived, but there was no such thing
сельской местности Жил да не было такого
Well, because people had everything of their own in the
Да ну потому что у людей было всё своё
cities, let's say in the nineties
городах вот в девяностые годы допустим
people were standing there, some kind of coupons were there And in
люди стояли какие-то талоны были там А в
threet And in thirty-three, on the other hand, in the
трит А в тридцать третьем на оборот в
city in Moscow you didn’t go hungry, you lived in
городе в Москве не голодали вы жили в
Moscow in thirty-three,
Москве в тридцать третьем году
you tell it as if you weren’t there, there
рассказываете как будто вы там нету
are no millions who died in Ukraine, there are
миллионов погибших в Украине есть
millions who died from hunger in Moscow,
миллионы погибших от голода в Москве
no  just look at one memorial
нету ни одной мемориальной
plaque in Moscow, there is not a
табли е раз смотрите в Москве нету ни
single memorial plaque and to those who died of
одной памятной доски да погибшим от
hunger during this year, not a single one in
голода ри рего года ни одной у вас в Мос
Mosro where
ро где
I am
ия
the sound in
ми звук
short they had What to eat yes But
короче у них было Что покушать да А вот
who is in the city Yes starvation coupons so in the
кто в городе Да голодали талоны так в
thirty-third  on the contrary,
тридцать третьем наоборот голодали от
those who were in the village were dying of hunger, and not those
голода умирали те кто был в селе а не те
who were in
кто был в
Moscow, today we have the Day of Remembrance of the Victims of the
Москве сегодня у нас День памяти жертв
Holodomor. The Day of Remembrance
голодомора День памяти
of the Victims of the Holodomor. That is, when
кого жертв голодомора То есть когда вот
in 1932-33
в ри тридцать второй тридцать третий год
Moscow took all the food from the Ukrainian residents
Москва забирала у украинских жителей всю
and took it to  Moscow and more than
еду и отвозил в Москву и более там
several million there died from hunger,
нескольких миллионов погибло от голода
you know the history well, yes, yes, you
прям историю хорошо знаете да да
taught it
учил
well, then tell me what
хорошо скажите тогда какие
territories were given to Ukraine from Russia;
территории от России были подарены
no gifts from Russian tsars;
никакие подарки русских царей
gifts can be given. Show what kind of gift.
подарки може Покажите какой подарок
What kind of Russian gift did you give from
Какой русский подарили подарок вы отте
Kata, they
Кату
stole it, they say, here’s a deed of
дарят они говорят вот грамота
gift  we give to someone, you can find
дарственная дарим тому-то можете найти
some gift that was given by Which
какую-то дарственную что подарил Какой
Tsar Which Tsar gave what to Ukraine give it to you now it
царь Какой царь что Украине подари вам
will be more convenient to log on to the computer on
удобнее будет сечас зайти с компьютер по
not just you say Which Tsar gave
не просто ты скажи Какой царь подарил
what to Ukraine and in what year
что Украине и в каком году меня
test me for my erudition in this
проверяйте на мою эрудированность в этом
matter Oh well  not on erudition And
вопросе Да ну не на эрудированность А
how
насколько ты
brainless you are Thank you for more
безмозглый Спасибо болье
information for today
сния на сегодня
Dem
Дем
year it was when Moscow took away the food of the
год было когда Москва забирала ВС еду
inhabitants of Ukraine and several
жителей Украины и там несколько
million died of hunger there today
миллионов погибло от голода вот сегодня
we honor the memory of these
чтим память этих
people I condole I just don’t know what to
людей Соболезную Я просто не знаю что
say you caught me badly I’m
сказать вы застали плохо меня
sorry What do you think  Why did Moscow
извиняюсь Как вы считаете Зачем Москва
take away all the food from people in Ukraine
забирала у людей в Украине всю
games I try not to touch I
еду игры я стараюсь не касаться У меня
have my life
есть моя жизнь
and I want to live
и я хочу прожить
it as best I can and how
её как бы как могу а как вы
can you so I’m going to it happily at
можете так иду к ней счастливо по
least I’m planning Ponya A good
крайней мере планирую Поня А хорошо
example uh if politicians Yes
например э если политики Да
uh  they will decide something, for example, to take away all your
ээ решат что-то например забрать у вас
food, Ani, they will take it away, and nothing can be done about it. Yeah, I
еду Ани заберут и тут ничего сделать
understand, that is, in
нельзя будет Ага понял то есть всё
short, despondency is decaying, yes, yes, that’s how it
короче тленны уныние да да Так Так оно и
is. And for you, well, that is, in such a
есть А вам Ну то есть в такой системе
coordinate system, you describe yourself as if
координат вы так себя описываете будто
you are a slave to this  systems Yes, we are all like that,
вы раб этой системы Да мы все такие
people are going to war, they were told
также вон люди идут на войну им сказали
that they got a summons, they didn’t come according to the
ити им повестка пришла не пришли они по
summons and they went to prison, you want to
повестке и ихн в тюрьму вы хотите
say that in Russia the people are
сказать что в России получается народ
slaves, or that how is it, in fact, it’s
рабы или что как это по сути
cool, it’s not like that, I won’t even eat it
да прикольно не так оно есть даже не
I had some doubts to argue with you,
буду спорить с вами были у меня
but I won’t argue.
некоторые сомнения но Спорить не
Maybe you have some questions for me,
буду Может у вас есть ко мне какие-то
no, good. I’ve already talked
вопросы нет хорошо Я уже тоже поговорил
happily, I don’t even need to convince them anymore. It’s
счастливо даже уже их не надо этоко
all your Grandma, in the
переубеждать уже все ваша Бабушка вот в
thirties, she didn’t tell you
тридцатых годах не рассказывала вам она
what year she was.  By the way, she was
какого года рождения Кстати она двадцать
born in the twenty-second year, she didn’t
второго года рождения она вам не
tell you. She didn’t tell you before the
рассказывала Она Вам не рассказывала до
war there about the Holodomor of the thirtieth
войны там про Голодомор тридцатого
thirty-second year in
тридцать второго года в
Moscow, this didn’t happen. Of course, in Moscow there
Москве такого не было Конечно в Москве
wasn’t any Holodomor. Perhaps in
Не было никакого голодомора Возможно на
Ukraine somewhere in the half, maybe there was a
Украине где-то в поол может о был
mores question Yes  why did it happen
морес вопрос Да почему так получилось
that in the Volga region and in Ukraine where
что в Поволжье да в Украине где
they grow bread and for one second there was
выращивают хлеб да одну секунду был
a famine? And at what point
голодомор А с какого пере одну секунду
100 years ago did this happen? Perhaps it
100 лет назад это произошло Возможно это
was possible No, most likely it was, yes there
было возможно Нет скорее всего было да
was some kind of famine and what does
какой-то был голодомор
this have to do with it now I look at it
причём Причём тут это сейчас я смотри я
just a historian, yes By training, I’m
просто историк да По образованию я вот
the kind of historian you are I want What kind of you
какой вы историк Я хочу Какие вас
wait, I’m watching Don’t interrupt, I
подождите я смотрите Не перебивайте я
want to understand For example, how are we today, the
хочу понять Вот например э как мы сейчас
modern generation, comprehending the events of
современное поколение осмысливая события
the Holodomor, so I can’t understand why they
голодомора вот я не могу понять почему в
didn’t grow wheat in Moscow Yes, but there was
Москве в Москве же пшеницу не выращивали
famine  there wasn’t, but in Ukraine, where
Да но голода не было а в Украине где
everyone grew wheat, there was famine. Well, where did
каждый выращивал пшеницу был голод Ну а
they get the idea that they didn’t grow wheat in Moscow?
с чего взяли что в Москве не выращивали
Well, because it’s a city. Well, what kind of things do
ше Ну потому что это город Ну какие у
you have? It’s a city. It’s clear. And in
вас это самое ну город Понятно А в
the suburbs they grew it, and look,
пригороде то выращивали да смотрите
the suburbs of Moscow weren’t
пригорода Москвы не
enough
хватало
for a second.  second If you are a historian,
од секу секунду секунду Если вы историк
then you should rely on some
то вы должны опираться на какие-то
historical documents facts axis what
исторические документы факты ось какие у
documents do you have that in Moscow they did not
вас документы есть что в Москве не
grow wheat under Moscow Look at
выращивали пшеницу под моско Смотри
the book of Daniil more precisely Yes, what is he himself, this
книга Даниил точе Да какая э он сам этот
Soviet scientist was a historian and then
советский учёный был историк да потом
Russian Yes, he made a collection  all
российский Да он сделал собрание всех
documents yes In the archives of the KGB of the USSR yes and
документов да В архивах КГБ СССР да и
showed Yes that uh all of Moscow Leningrad Yes they
показал Да что э всю Москву Ленинград Да
fed uh grain exported from Ukraine
кормили э вывезенный из Украины
one
зерном одну
second where are these documents how high
секунду где эти документы какие высокую
I look at you I told you here is
какую я вам смотрите я вам сказал зате
the link to what this is this you
ссылку на что вот это вот вот это
understand this is your Golosova  look
понимаете это ваше Голосова смотрите
come look Come to the library
заходите смотрите Заходите в библиотеку
why Ukrainian and not
а почему именно украинские а не
Kuban not Voronezh
кубанские не воронежские
thief What does Ukraine have to do with Cuba Voronezh
ворое Причём тут Украина Куба Воронеж
is also Ukraine Ukrainian people
это тоже Украина украинские люди там
live there young man How
живут молодой человек Как ты
confused you are, you need all the historical
запутался надо на всё исторические
references
ссылки
Dava the historian Look, if only we could turn up the sound at the
Дава историк Смотри вот если бы тыл на
Faculty of History
историческом факультете
look again That is, you You are
крутим звук смотри ещ раз То есть ты Ты
given that they
дано
took grain from Ukraine at zero rate, not
из Украины забирали зерно под ноль не то
that they took some of it Yes, in order to feed
что там часть взяли Да чтобы кормить
Moscow, yes they took it at zero price,
Москву да забирали под ноль людей
they left people to starve to death, yes And in
оставляли на голодную смерть да А в
Moscow they didn’t die of hunger like this and so
Москве от голода не умирали так
and that you agree with this
так так и что ты согласен с этим
yes Well,
да Ну
probably there was such a need
вероятно необходимость была
to do so that several million
сделать чтоб умерло сколько-то миллионов
people would die on one territory in the World Cup, the
людей на одной территории в ЧМ
need,
необходимость
look, I explain it very simply, look, if
смотри объясняю очень просто смотри если
you are a little stupid and stupid, but most
ты немножко туповат и глупова а скорее
likely American, look, very simply,
всего американской смотри очень просто
Comrade Lin, as
товарищ лин как
Russia said, Russia is 100 years behind Europe
сказал Россия отстала от Европы на 100
for us  it is necessary to cover this
лет нам надо необходимо пробежать этот
period in 20
промежуток за за 20
years. So they ran it, they
лет Вот они его пробежали они с
built a lot of factories from 1917 to 1941, so they
1941 построили массу заводов так
ran it correctly, they built it, and
правильно пробежали построили а людей
why did they take people
забрали всю еду зачем у людей ещё е я те
away from them?  I didn’t
отключил звук Ещё раз чтобы ты не
pile on and I’ll ask the question again
наваливал и задам ещё раз вопрос
they built factories steamships launched people into space
построили заводы пароходы в космос людей
Why tens of millions of people
запустили Зачем десятки миллионов людей
were starved to death Why am I giving you a simple example
заморили голодом Зачем простой пример
everything went n Come on come on they
тебе привожу всё пошёл н Давай давай они
all can’t pathologically admit it’s
все они не могут патологически признать
just Yes they all understand damn the factories
просто Да они все понимают блин заводы
built what the [ __ ] factories Damn yes
постро какие нахрен заводы Блин да
Millions of people were simply destroyed by
Миллионы людей просто уничтожены были
starvation, you say the factories
голодной смертью ты рассказываешь заводы
were built by an idiot just an idiot, subscribe
построили идиот просто идиот подпишись
to Migra right now, the axis of wine and
на мигра прям зараз ось вин а
popk is more and more YouTube, taking us
попк це дуже и дуже YouTube заня нас
through the sgr to the new ban and even a lot of videos, I
через сгр в ньй бан и дуже багато вдео
won’t show people at all times, I won’t show
не показу людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams For Tom  togo
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
mi Mali operational link ppi directly contagion
ми Мали оперативний звязок ппи прямо
and while there in telegra okm video sche tezh
зараз а пок там в телегра окм видео ще
tsikava and korisna information and we are
теж цикава и корисна информация и мы
guilty of you trim postiy
повинни з вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write
пиши